

21 Watts Avenue Rochester ME1 1RX Phone: +44 7828 90 66 92 E-mail: srivas at gmail dot com

Academic site: cs.kent.ac.uk/people/staff/sc785/

Srivas Chennu

Nationality: British

## **Profile**

I specialise in turning data science problems into scalable solution prototypes for real-world applications. A computational neuroscientist with 10+ years of R&D experience, I have a background in computer science. Have worked as a data science consultant and as a software engineer.

## **Employment**

**Data Science Consultant** Rsrchxchange Ltd., UK 2017-present

- Developed latent factor model to power recommendation engine for customisation of user experience.
- Built text analysis model based on neural networks to discover natural language content similarity.

**Assistant Professor** University of Kent, UK 2016-present

**Senior Research Associate** 

University of Cambridge, UK

2010-present

- Develop machine learning tools for modelling human cognition
- · Build monitoring and brain-computer interfacing systems for healthcare applications
- Have attracted £600,000+ of competitive research grant funding

**Member of Technical Staff** 

Oracle Corporation, India

2002-2004

• Software engineer in the Oracle Reports team, a part of Oracle's Internet Application Server platform

#### **Education**

PhD in Computer Science

University of Kent, Canterbury, UK

2006-2009

2004-2006

Thesis title: The temporal spotlight of attention: computational and electrophysiological

*explorations* (approved with no corrections at viva held on 16<sup>th</sup> March 2010)

MSc in Information and Hamburg University of Technology **Communication Systems** 

Hamburg, Germany

Overall ECTS grade: 1.3 (Very Good; Passed with Distinction)

BEng in Computer Science and

Visveswaraiah Technological University

1998-2002

**Engineering** 

Bangalore, India

Overall percentage score - 81.46% (First Class with Distinction)

### Writing and Public Speaking

- Published 40+ peer-reviewed scientific articles in prominent journals, with 18 as primary author
- · Prepared and delivered more than 25+ invited talks at international scientific conferences
- · Have given public talks and demos at Cambridge Science Festival and New Scientist Live

## Media Coverage and Public Engagement

- My research and data visualisation has been extensively profiled by online and print **news**, including the BBC, New Scientist, Scientific American, Der Spiegel, Science, and Wired Magazine
- · Have given radio and TV interviews and expert commentary to the BBC World Service, BBC Radio 4 Today & 5 Live, BBC News 24, Discovery Channel, and Al Jazeera TV

## Research and Technical Skills

- Machine Learning, Data Science and Visualisation
- · Digital Signal Processing and Time Series Analysis

- · Graph Theory and Network Analysis
- Parametric, Non-parametric and Bayesian Statistical Methods
- Cognitive Neuroscience and Computational Modelling
- · Computer Networking and Security, Operating Systems
- Tools: Python, MATLAB, R, Apache Spark, Hadoop
- Programming Languages: Python, MATLAB, JAVA, C, C++

#### **Project Management**

- Manage and support team of 2 postdoctoral scientists and 3 PhD students.
- Perform complex data analytics and timely reporting as a part of ongoing research studies
- Regularly **present research progress** at annual collaboration meetings
- Have supervised 10 research projects and regularly mentor students

#### Academic and Organisational Experience

- Peer-reviewer for reputed scientific journals including PLOS and Frontiers
- · Have organised international conferences funded by the Royal Society
- · Have served as an **examiner** for MPhil and PhD research theses

# **Previous Research Experience**

**Research Assistant** Fraunhofer Institute for Telecommunications 2005-2006

Berlin, Germany

• Worked on the EU-funded IST *Multi Service Access Everywhere* project on QoS-aware broadband internet access using resilient optical access rings

Research Assistant Hamburg University of Technology 2004-2005 Hamburg, Germany

• Developed an algorithmic methodology for verifiable decentralization of modular real-time control systems represented as timed automata

Project Trainee Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore, India 2002

· Implemented algorithms and user interface software for display and manipulation of image formats

#### **Selected Academic Publications**

- Chennu, S., Annen, J., Wannez, S., Thibaut, A., Chatelle, C., Cassol, H., Martens, G., et al. 2017. Brain networks predict metabolism, diagnosis and prognosis at the bedside in disorders of consciousness.
  Brain (IF 10.1), 140(8), 2120-2132.
- Chennu, S., Finoia, P. et al. 2014. Spectral signatures of reorganised brain networks in disorders of consciousness. *PLOS Computational Biology* (*IF 4.8*), 10(10), e1003887
- Chennu, S., Noreika, V. et al. 2013. Expectation and Attention in Hierarchical Auditory Prediction. *The Journal of Neuroscience (IF 6.7)*, 33(27), 11194-11205.
- Cruse, D., Chennu, S. et al. 2011. Bedside detection of awareness in the vegetative state: a cohort study. *The Lancet (IF 39.2)*, 378(9809), 2088-2094.
- **Chennu**, S., Alsufyani, A., Filetti, M., Owen, A. & Bowman, H. 2013. The cost of space independence in P300-BCI spellers. *Journal of NeuroEngineering and Rehabilitation*, 10(1), 82.